Segun Akanbi

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

A passionate and hardworking software engineer with over 5 years of experience solving business problems using technology, with a solid background in Computer Science and Graphic Design. I have developed excellent critical thinking skills from working on several projects with great teams. I'm always eager to spotlight innovative ideas and bring them to life for the betterment of the world.

CONTACT

⊠ akanbisegun1@gmail.com

+2349069540681

n www.linkedin.com/in/akanbi-s

www.github.com/shegsdev

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Full Stack Engineer

GIFTEDHANDS TECHNOLOGIES March 2018 - Present

Built a user management application for a cooperative society to manage member savings, loans and weekly meeting reports. Developed an e-commerce platform for therapeutic products using WordPress and Elementor. Developed a web crawler for an application that finds professors with relevant expertise for specific courses at any UK university.

TECHNOLOGIES: NodeJS, Django, Laravel, ReactJS, VueJS, Vuex, NextJS, Python, Reat Native, Typescript, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, SCSS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Wordpress, Elementor, Amazon EC2, DynamoDB.

Senior Frontend Engineer

AFRICA PRUDENTIAL PLC

March 2022 - May 2023

Contributed my expertise in developing a multi-tenant application for managing shareholders. Converted UI mockups into quality and reusable code. Collaborated with back-end developers, QA testers, and product managers to implement business requirements. Managed specific application modules and ensured user-friendliness and mobile responsiveness.

TECHNOLOGIES: ReactJS, Ant Design, SCSS, Jira.

Full Stack Engineer

LIFESTORES HEALTHCARE

November 2020 - September 2021

Collaborated with other engineers on developing an ERP system. Worked on several features of the system including the admin dashboard, customer feedback module, product order return functionality, chain management system, payment system and many other features and updates.

TECHNOLOGIES: Django, GraphQL, ReactJS, SQL, Docker, EC2, Jenkins, Jira, Pivotal Tracker, StyledComponents, Dexie, Material UI

Lead Software Engineer

NEURAL TECHNOLOGIES November 2018 - December 2020

Participated in the requirement analysis phase, architecture and database for a cross-border financial software. Built backend APIs from start to finish and deployed them to Heroku Cloud Platform. Designed and developed a Feed Formulator Algorithm for farm animals. Manage AWS infrastructure.

TECHNOLOGIES: JavaScript, Python, NodeJS, ReactJS, Flask, SCSS, AWS Amplify, Jira, Pivotal Tracker, Trello.

Associate Software Engineer

ASH NELSON PARTNERS May 2019 - June 2020

Contributed my expertise to developing a sentiment-based Brand Reputation and Performance System. Built and deployed microservices and integrated them into existing solutions. Programmed a script for an ETL pipeline using Python and AWS. Contributed to software engineering expertise in the development of products using Agile methodologies. Systems Integration and hands-on Development of Enterprise AML Applications using JavaScript and Python. Planning, Designing, Testing and Deployment of Anti-Fraud Solutions for Commercial Banks and Fintech organisations. Deployment of OEM Cybersecurity equipment.

TECHNOLOGIES: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, AWS S3 and EC2, Elasticsearch, Selenium, Scrapy, Tweepy, Kibana, Bitbucket, Jira.

Web Development Intern

HIIT PLC April 2017 - July 2017

Designed static websites using modern web technologies. Honed my Graphics Design skills for application interface development. Collaborated with other interns to work on group projects. Acquired customer relations and representative skills.

TECHNOLOGIES: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, CorelDraw, Photoshop.

EDUCATION

■ B.Sc., Computer Science

UNIVERSITY OF THE PEOPLE 2020

Associate Degree, Computer Science

YABA COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY 2016 - 2018

SKILLS

JavaScript Python PHP Node.js Express.js Django Flask Laravel Codelgniter React.js Vue.js Next.js React Native

Wordpress Redux Vuex Git MySQL PostgreSQL MongoDB GraphQL Elasticsearch DynamoDB Figma Adobe XD

CorelDraw Twitter Bootstrap TailwindCSS SCSS Material UI Docker Amazon EC2 AWS CloudWatch Amazon Comprehend

Heroku Netlify

INTERESTS

AI, ML, Music, Pencil Rendering